<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microservices on Sundar</title>
    <link>/tags/microservices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microservices on Sundar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/microservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Journey from Monolith to Microservices - AWS Story</title>
      <link>/publications/aws_microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/aws_microservices/</guid>
      <description>This was a workshop cum training program for faculties of engineering colleges across India. I had the chance to talk about the evolution of modern day architecture - Cloud Native, Microservices. In this talk, I covered the tech journey of how amazon grew from a online book buying platform to a massive ecommerce market place. In the due process, covered the following topics
Started as a 2 tier architecture Grew into a monolith with multi tier architecture Evolved into a Service Oriented architecture Birth of AWS - Amazon web services NoSQL movement Microservices all the way Serverless/Lambda </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A no/low code developer platform for building ML &amp; RPA solutions</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/nocode_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/nocode_platform/</guid>
      <description>This low code platform&amp;rsquo;s objective is to ease the lives of ML and RPA developers by providing a visual drag and drop interface to build solutions for ML and RPA needs. Architected the entire platform right from ground up.
Tech Stack Frontend React as UI library Redux for state management REST APIs for CRUD Electron for desktop application Backend NestJS for business logic ML microservices NodeRed for low-code development DataStore MongoDB Integrations MLFlow for machine learning lifecycle Programming Languages TypeScript JavaScript Python </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
