<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web-Development on Sundar</title>
    <link>/tags/web-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web-Development on Sundar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Have a Mobile-First App Idea? Think Web First</title>
      <link>/blog/mobile_first_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/mobile_first_blog/</guid>
      <description>Have a Mobile-First App Idea? Think Web First You’ve got a mobile-first app idea. The instinct is to start with native Android or iOS development. But before you commit months of time and resources, here’s something worth considering from years of building and launching apps:&#xA;Start with a responsive web app.&#xA;Here’s why this approach can accelerate your progress and reduce overhead—especially when validating an idea.&#xA;Why the Web First Approach Makes Sense Let’s break down the advantages of going web-first:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools that make me productive - Web Development</title>
      <link>/blog/tools-that-make-me-productive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/tools-that-make-me-productive/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to share and list down the tools that I use for my projects (web-development in particular).&#xA;VS Code I have become a super fan of VS-Code, so so light weight and it has become the defacto Editor for any JS projects - frontend as well as backend. I use it for few of my python projects as well it works as a Charm (infact better than PyCharm.. :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front End development Analogy</title>
      <link>/blog/front-end-analogies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/front-end-analogies/</guid>
      <description>Whenever we learn about some topics or if you are teaching someone, I always felt analogies from day to day life makes a greater impact to a person&amp;rsquo;s understanding. This post is my take on analogy of technologies/terminologies/people involved in front end development.&#xA;I am going to compare building a website to building a house where :&#xA;HTML(HyperText Markup Language) would be the raw building materials namely bricks, steels, cement. These help you in building the skeleton or structure of your house.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
