<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>React Native on Sundar</title>
    <link>/tags/react-native/</link>
    <description>Recent content in React Native on Sundar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 12:41:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/react-native/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tuition Management App</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/tutora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/tutora/</guid>
      <description>This is about developing a mobile app for small scale/home based tutors. The app is primarily targetted to reduce the administation hassles of managing/running a online/physical classes. The backend is cloud native and frontend is built using React Native.
Tech Stack Frontend React Native as UI framework Mobx for state management GraphQL/REST clients for CRUD Backend AWS Serverless for business logic AWS API Gateway for routing AWS Cognito for authentication AWS S3 for storage AWS Event Bridge for integrations with third party apps DataStore Mongo DB Atlas for storing application data Mongo Realm as the persistence layer interface exposing GraphQL server Integrations Twilio for SMS and Email Programming Languages TypeScript JavaScript </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ERP Product suite</title>
      <link>/projects/creations/procure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/creations/procure/</guid>
      <description>The product is an offering of a typical ERP suite which was being migrated from PHP to MERN. Was involved in both frontend development in React and also backend in NodeJS.
Tech Stack Frontend Mobile App built on React Native Web App built on React Storybook for building reusable components Redux for state management Urql/REST clients for CRUD Chrome extension built with React Backend AWS Serverless for business logic AWS API Gateway for routing Auth0 for authentication AWS S3 for file storage Lerna for package management DataStore Postgres/MongoDB as data stores ElasticSearch for product data store Programming Languages TypeScript JavaScript </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
