<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavaScript on Sundar</title>
    <link>/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavaScript on Sundar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 17:09:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Callback props to a React Add to Calendar library</title>
      <link>/projects/contributions/react_add_to_calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/contributions/react_add_to_calendar/</guid>
      <description>Add to Calendar is a react package to add an event to calendar (Google, Outlook, Apple etc). I needed a way to handle the calendar dropdown close event when the mouse is clicked anywhere on the document. I added a callback function that would be passed as a param</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Added support for thousand separator in Angular localization library</title>
      <link>/projects/contributions/angular_i10n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/contributions/angular_i10n/</guid>
      <description>Angular l10n is a Angular localization library that supports text translation, formatting dates and numbers. The number directive that comes as part of this library was missing the thousand&amp;rsquo;s separator. My PR was to add support to the thousand&amp;rsquo;s separator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A-Z of JavaScript</title>
      <link>/blog/a-z-of-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/a-z-of-javascript/</guid>
      <description>This is my collection of A-to-Z terms that one should know if they are into serious javascript programming.
Async/Await Async and Await are new features introduced in the language to make asynchronous code block look synchronous and more importantly make it more readable.
Brendan Eich Brendan Eich is the creator of JavaScript. He created the language in a matter of 10 days when working for Netscape Navigator. Due credit to be given to him for creating this language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
