<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Angular on Sundar</title>
    <link>/tags/angular/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Angular on Sundar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/angular/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Added support for thousand separator in Angular localization library</title>
      <link>/projects/contributions/angular_i10n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 17:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/contributions/angular_i10n/</guid>
      <description>Angular l10n is a Angular localization library that supports text translation, formatting dates and numbers. The number directive that comes as part of this library was missing the thousand&amp;rsquo;s separator. My PR was to add support to the thousand&amp;rsquo;s separator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Angular vs React</title>
      <link>/blog/angular-vs-react---my-take-on-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/angular-vs-react---my-take-on-it/</guid>
      <description>Ahh..I am sure you would have read umpteen number of blogs/articles comparing React, Angular (and Vue). Well this is going to be my version of it after having had a chance to work on both of them. I have developed a decent amount of projects in Angular and in React and kind of got a good grasp on both of these to write about their similarities/differences.&#xA;For starters, both of them are used to build SPAs and good at what they are supposed to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Difference between AngularJS and Angular</title>
      <link>/blog/angularjs-vs-angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/angularjs-vs-angular/</guid>
      <description>Angular the framework as this is what the Angular team would like to call, has evolved(and evolving) from being the most popular front end JavaScript framework over the last 5 years to a framework that has transformed itself to survive and be a leader for years to come. All references to Angular points to the version 2 and above and AngularJS means Angular 1.x.&#xA;In this post, we would be seeing how different is Angular and what are the new additions it is bringing to the world of Single Page App development.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
